engineering.tumblr.com 2007-12-31

# Tumblr

Tumblr, Inc. (“Tumblr”) takes the private nature of your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy (which we adapted from a policy originally provided by [Automattic](http://www.automattic.com/) ([WordPress.com](http://www.wordpress.com/))) describes how we treat the information we collect when you visit and use the website available at Tumblr.com (the “Website”) and is made available under the **Creative Commons Sharealike** license. Please read this notice very carefully. 

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Tumblr collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Tumblr’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Tumblr’s visitors use its Website. From time to time, Tumblr may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its Website. 

Tumblr also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Tumblr does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below. 

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to the Website choose to interact with Tumblr in ways that require Tumblr to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Tumblr gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog at Tumblr.com to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Tumblr – by purchasing access to the Akismet comment spam prevention service, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Tumblr collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Tumblr. Tumblr does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities. 

Tumblr does not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that a child has provided Tumblr with personally identifiable information without the consent of his or her parent or guardian, please contact us at [support@tumblr.com](mailto:support@tumblr.com). If Tumblr becomes aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete such information. 

## Aggregated Statistics

Tumblr may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Website. For instance, Tumblr may monitor the most popular blogs on the Tumblr.com site to help identify spam. Tumblr may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Tumblr does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. 

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Tumblr discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Tumblr’s behalf or to provide services available at the Website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using the Website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. In addition, in some cases we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Tumblr or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Tumblr goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquiror of Tumblr may continue to use your personal and non-personal information only as set forth in this policy. Otherwise, Tumblr will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. 

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations or as described above, Tumblr discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Tumblr believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Tumblr, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the Tumblr Website and have supplied your email address, Tumblr may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Tumblr and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Tumblr takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information. 

You should also be aware that if you submit information to “chat rooms,” “forums” or “message boards” such information becomes public information, meaning that you lose any privacy rights you might have with regards to that information. Such disclosures may also increase your chances of receiving unwanted communications. 

For users outside the United States, please note that any personally-identifiable information you enter into the Website will be transferred out of your country and into the United States. You consent to such transfer through your use of the Website. You also warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States. 

## Links to Third Party Sites

This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by Tumblr. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Tumblr does not own or control, or employees that Tumblr does not manage. The Website contains links to third party websites. Any information you provide to, or that is collected by, third-party sites may be subject to the privacy policies of those sites, if any. We encourage you to read such privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit. It is the sole responsibility of such third parties to adhere to any applicable restrictions on the disclosure of your personally-identifying information, and Tumblr and its affiliates shall not be liable for wrongful use or disclosure of your personally-identifying information by any third party. 

## Security

All non-personally-identifying information, potentially personally-identifying and personally identifying-information described above is stored on restricted database servers. 

## Choice/Opt-out

If we ever send you information by e-mail concerning new products, services or information that you did not expressly request, we will provide you with an e-mail address by which you may request no further notices. 

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Tumblr uses cookies to help Tumblr identify and track visitors, their usage of the Tumblr Website, and their Website access preferences. Tumblr visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the Tumblr Website, with the drawback that certain features of Tumblr’s Website may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Tumblr may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Tumblr’s sole discretion. If we do then we’ll notify you by posting the amended policy on the Website or by emailing you of the nature of the modifications along with a link to the modified document so that you can review it. In all cases, use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. 

## Review and Access

Upon your request, we will provide you with a summary of the information we collect about you. You will have the opportunity to correct, update, modify or delete this information by sending an e-mail to [support@tumblr.com](mailto:support@tumblr.com). Please note that some information may remain in our records after deletion of your account. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this policy or our site in general, please contact us at [support@tumblr.com](mailto:support@tumblr.com).
